I didn't date much in high school
it's very interested in dating in my
growing up years and the feeling just
wasn't mutual it just wasn't what I need
to figure out is what do women want
and rather than consulting any women
figure it out on my own and and the
conclusion I came to was that women want
a man who can do Star Wars impressions
and the impression that I do well is the
the the snow planet the creatures they
wrote through the snow like horses the
kangaroo rats on steroids those are the
Tontons that's right here's my
impression of the Todd Don here we go I
didn't date much in high school
I married an extrovert someone who likes
to sneak her thoughts on the outside I'm
more of an introvert myself I'd like to
think my own thoughts in here and a lot
of introverts and extroverts get married
don't they cuz it works out pretty good
cuz one likes to talk and the other has
to listen that's right
and if you're an extrovert you need to
hear what I'm about to say it says that
this might change your life actually we
introverts we think you're fascinating
we do we love your level of detail in
your stories we do but we've only got so
much room up here and then it starts to
clogged up with your data then we have
to go to our happy place to cope for me
that Star Wars the little place in my
head where I go to respite from her
onslaught of data it should be like did
you see Jenny last week in church
no why well she was wearing a pink
blouse with concentric circles
reminiscent of an exploding supernova
her jeans were modest and tasteful the
color of deep blue gemstones on the
Beltline sapphires onyx precious stones
textures lighting scents hidden feelings
spiritual vibes choirs of angels singing
over the earth black holes alternate
universes pretty shoes are you listening
[Applause]
and that's when you extroverts asked
that question were you listening what
was I saying some of you want to laugh
at this but you're sitting by that
special someone right now laugh leader
I'm Darrin I'll be your comedian this
evening I what can I tell you about
myself I'm an allergy sufferer any
allergy sufferers out there Willers it
to two things organic and inorganic
matter didn't think I had allergies
didn't think I had him I just thought I
had a really bad cold since preschool so
my mom she used to treat the problem she
used to hose me down with vicks vapor
rub which she liked a little too much on
me the air above me always had this
distorted look to it all the time
yeah I get on the school bus all the
kids got emotional I can't still like a
girl tried to hug me in high school she
got cured of her asthma's
praise the Lord so I went to the allergy
clinic that was fun we're gonna give you
15 shots in your arm I'm like what a
happy place
they shot formaldehyde in my arm to see
if I to react to it I did I put my
doctor in a headlock of it thanks for
taking me for formaldehyde next time so
one wants to store me in a jar with some
frogs I'm gonna say no I'm allergic to
poison I'm allergic to wheat eggs milk
and sugar have nightmares about the
muffin man I'm allergic to dust mites
any I dust mite allergies out there yeah
see and I have microscopic creatures
that live in your pillow I don't know
what's worse being allergic to dust
mites or just knowing they exist I'll
wake up at like 3:00 in the morning
there he I sleep with a helmet in a tick
collar now my wife has lost that loving
feeling
could be the vicks vapor rub I'm not
exactly sure what's going on there I'm
married I have four kids four boys all
under the age of 21 four boys so thank
you for boys not gonna be able to resell
my house at any time just gonna burn it
down when we're done want to bring them
up right wanna you know discipline the
kids bring them up right we're not very
good at it well well we weren't I mean
we tried the timeout thing that didn't
seem to work
tried to withdrawing privileges thing
that didn't seem to work so we ended up
going with the nuclear option and we
make out in front of our kids it works
very well
so you're not gonna mow the lawn you're
not gonna mobile hon come here honey
highly recommended the Arbitron buxus my
kids a little a little crazy you know
and I called my wife at home she's
dealing with those kids so yeah it's
kind of weird if you call a spouse at
home when they're dealing with the kids
it's kind of hard because you can't tell
if she's talking to you on the phone or
yelling at the kids do you know anybody
it's like a schizophrenic conversation
I'll call her say hi honey she's like hi
why you bothering me now why are you
picking right now to bother me I wish
you were here I wish you were here don't
make me come over there
drop it what have you been up to nothing
what are you up to I love you do you
really love me you still there yeah boy
the kids are really acting up tonight
huh what do you mean the kids are with
my mother I did that to the poor woman
life is crazy though isn't it folks too
much technology out there now it's
everywhere you can't call a business
anymore without a computer ants are
gonna phone and the problem with
computers answering the phone they can't
hear you call it business and the
computer will say please say your
account number and you say it we didn't
understand what you said
please Reese a your account number and
you say it we still didn't understand
you hahahahaha
please key in your account number we're
sorry you must press pound after King in
your account number please Ricky in your
account number please verify your
account number please sing and dance
your account number
imagine a sculpture chiseled out of
limestone inspired by your account
number describe it for us
we're sorry must press pound after
describing your sculpture are you sure
this is your account number let's start
over please smoke signal your account
number please telepathically blast your
account number all right please hold the
average wait time 45 minutes and then
they play a song that you hate over and
over and over again till your brain is
bleeding then you get a human being on
the phone what's the first question they
ask you you just lost your mind and
that's what I'm sorry takes an hour to
get my account number please listen
the first number is three
the second number seven I'm sorry was
press pound after threatening to hurt
yourself please continue to listen
[Applause]
just need to calm down because there are
a lot of fun I feel like being
vulnerable with you guys I had buck
teeth growing up that was fun
buck teeth why don't they call it buck
teeth you know I've never seen a deer
crossing the road
[Laughter]
maybe that's why the deer are out of the
road they're trying to straighten their
teeth is like the problem with buck
teeth does no matter what your feeling
on the inside you always have the same
expression on the outside so I got
braces because I didn't want to look
like a freak anymore
that really helped yeah five pounds of
metal in my face
I couldn't even swim my head kept
pointing toward ruined or them how many
of you had braces quite a few oh yeah
and then you remember the plaster forms
that you got in the beginning did you
all right you know you blocked that
memory out if you don't know they take a
good to fit you for braces they take a
couple of frisbees fill them full of wet
plaster shove them in your mouth to make
a little plaster statue of your teeth I
was like why so we knew what your teeth
looked like I have an idea
but I wouldn't mind so much but I gag
really easy didn't be gag easy and like
a toothbrush or something I can't gag on
sunlight at all
she said frisbees in my mouth out in a
hole
[Music]
[Applause]
the orthodontist got mad at me for that
he's like hey just try to relax
who relaxes like that I don't think he
goes home after a long days of work I
got on wide hall
then they put rubber bands in the braces
right and the problem of the rubber
bands in the braces they shoot out of
your mouth and inopportune times anytime
i donít p1 would shoot out my English
teacher had to wear safety goggles today
class we're gonna learn about war then
not proud of this but one time I shot a
rubberband into the orthodontist mouth
[Applause]
is a bad day for him you need to brush
more in it
[Applause]
why sure love it here it's so beautiful
here and the people here are so just
lovely and fun to talk to and your
safety conscious here I like that about
you I'm staying at a hotel with an
indoor pool
that's very safety conscious because you
swim outdoors most of the year here you
die I noticed that really safety
conscious you're swimming in the indoor
pool you look on the ceiling above you
there's there's sprinklers case the
water catches fire never thought of that
tables have umbrellas over them you know
in case the sprinklers go off you know
nobody wants to get wet at the pool
never a lifeguard on duty every guess
you guys are do it yourselfers just to
do it yourself life preserver on the
wall plus it gonna help me if I'm having
trouble even if somebody through it I
think he's drilled splash it's not
coming down I'll talk to the manager
where you got the hook on the wall with
140 foot handle I guess you can save
someone's life without leaving the
comfort of your hotel room
I'm saving lives I love the hot tub
myself do you like hot tubs just yeah
that's how I thaw I like the hot tub I
don't know if you like me though if I'm
sitting in a hot tub and a stranger sits
in the water with me
I get really kind of a strange kind of
nervousness about that and I'm trying to
figure out why do I get so nervous with
strangers in the hot tub and I think
it's because complete strangers don't
sit with me in the tub at home and if
they did I wouldn't treat them the same
way you know taking a bath at home some
dude walks in sits down I'm like where
are you from just your first time to my
house how interesting so I've always
been nervous about strangers in the hot
tub and and I'm walking toward the hot
tub and there's four ladies sitting in
the hot tub and that makes me nervous
cuz you're ladies you know but to make
it worse I don't even know if you ladies
are aware that you do this but when
you're in a pack together you stare
collectively and it is the meanest thing
you people do
just for women women going yes so that
made me walk faster than I should have
and I sat in the water with him to
quicken the ladies might not understand
this next part just try to follow along
but guys at 9 cubic feet of air trapped
in my shorts like 90 psi grip on the
side of the hot tub trying to look
normal but if I didn't like all that
pressure I was gonna flip upside down
before I let all the pressure out it was
the blast would flip all the ladies
something so I came up with a quick plan
I thought I'm gonna squeeze the shorts
gently gonna make little bubbles
to match the bubbles in the hot tub you
know who's gonna notice that everyone
because I wasn't little bubbles was one
gigantic nuclear Bala and all the women
it he said the wrong thing
pardon me
I was just trying to relieve the
pressure the pressure in my short the
pressures gone lady hard to be me it's
talking to my mom today yeah hey where
you going I said I'm on a dry bar comedy
sit down she says she said that be
careful there's nothing gets dry bar
it's Jesus variance she's a worrier mom
do you ever worry your mom and you know
yeah there's nothing like it is it
everything is just be careful be careful
be careful mom for breakfast can I have
cereal be careful you could fall asleep
and drown where your water wings I was
15 before I realized that hot dogs
become a tiny note choke pieces the
first time she felt comfortable letting
me stay home alone my wife went on a
women's retreat for crying out
but she never raised her voice in US
isn't that unusual it was always just be
careful I love you just an angel that
floated down from heaven married my
father I love you Tara never raised her
voice never yelled well except for that
hour before company came over she became
a different creature at that point
where is your father
strangely enough he had disappeared
[Music]
my house is already cleats you wanted to
see clean a place this company would
never go it'll go up into the attic and
coat the insulation fibers would you
want company over that was that picky we
were looking through your vacuum cleaner
bag we found dirt you people are
disgusting
we were dusting under doorknobs and
vacuuming out closets she was cracking
the whip and company showed up then she
was an angel I was still a little dense
at the dinner table one of the company's
kids build their Malcolm
[Music]
[Applause]
that's just evil but we got to watch out
for evil in the world my friends evil is
everywhere got to watch out for it you
got to avoid it there's even evil
machines now oh yes you've ever gone to
the eye doctor and had to use the
glaucoma checking machine that's an evil
regime they took you for glaucoma by
blasting air in your eye when was that
ever a good idea like well so we're
gonna check you for glaucoma just look
into people we'll check you for block
used to read the chart kind of thing you
actually don't see anything
well so we're pretty sure you don't have
glaucoma
you need an eyeball to have glaucoma
the good news is you'll never have
glaucoma in this eye right here it's an
evil machine have you ever gone to the
dentist and wrapped your lips around the
saliva sucker if you commit your lips to
the saliva sucker you're gonna have a
hard time breaking that commitment
shouldn't they turn the suction down if
your bellybutton is whistling I thought
I was gonna have gas and reverse how do
you explain that to your daddies like
did you cut the cheese evil even in some
of our recreational areas there's evil
there you gotta watch out for these
waterslide parks the summit you know the
big tree death drop water slides
four-story tall straight down who
invented this instrument of torture for
recreation party yeah we want to ride
that is all the horror falling off a
cliff drown and lose a layer of skin at
the same time fun they say it's not
dangerous but it's bit your body out
into a small water coffin
notice that it's not a pool because you
fit your body into a pool you're moving
your body would skip oh they have two
rules on that slide the first rule is
you got to plug your nose the second
rule is you got to cross your legs the
second rule is the most important rule
if you don't plug your nose water
springing up your nose but if you don't
cross your legs water is spraying out of
your nose that's evil
I love it here my dad used to bring us
out camping this way yeah my dad brought
us camping out here you have a lot of
lovely beautiful campgrounds around here
he didn't bring us to any of those
he brought us all the cheap was he
brought us the camp fund maker have
these doesn't camp fund maker oh I'll
tell you about it it seems like a
hi-tech campground but because it has
speakers making announcements you think
oh that's kind of Star Trek yeah I guess
but the speaker's short out during the
announcements cuz they're cheap see here
an announcement like today at camp fund
maker we're going to at the but never
ever go by them or you might die here at
camp fund maker so we're camping there
and one night the sky turns green and it
starts to really storm and then where
I've come from that means we're gonna
have a tornado I was really scared and
they wanted we didn't have a tornado and
they wanted to tell us that I think what
they wanted to say was there's no danger
no danger repeat no tornado no tornado
prepare to meet the Sun tomorrow from
your friends here at camp fund maker and
all we hear is so I heart camping oh do
you rent videos anymore does anybody do
that at the store I don't do that
anymore I mean I do it off the internet
now that's kind of nice but our video
store in our town is a little bit sad
you get the right case but it was
usually the wrong video in the case that
can ruin date night actually cuz my wife
would send me to the video store is it
get something we both like none of this
science fiction stuff get something we
both like something with royalty in it
so I got alien cuz it's got a queen in
his butt that was a nice compromise if
you haven't seen the movie alien a
though the alien takes over your body
and leaps out of your stomach in a walk
I thought this is gonna be great she's
gonna love it I got it home I pop it in
without looking it was your first
trimester of pregnancy home educational
video and I was very upset but I felt
worse for the pregnant woman who got the
video that I wanted to rent
she said my wife said we should get a
cat why our lives are not complete what
if I don't want our lives to be complete
we should get a cat anyway
okay you pick it out dear you know not
everyone is gifted at picking out a cat
she came home bleeding profusely down
her arm I said what happened to you she
said I kitten bit me I said Oh what did
you do to it she said I brought it home
to love can you help me get it out of
the back seat it's a little feisty this
thing hunted us
you ever flick your hair back like that
think it would die for your neck if you
wiggle your toes you'd find him under
the couch later mark poor children are
lying in bed and I daddy is there a
monster under my bed I'm like yes I'll
let your feet touch the ground try to
survive thank your mother how do you
discipline a cat how do you discipline
the cat we try to spray bottles she just
thought it was a drink so the vet said
give the cat value value for the cat the
viewer tried to force-feed pills to
Lucifer I went to the ER twice then the
vet said get the cat spayed very painful
surgery but he will take care of the
problem get her spayed so I got the cat
spayed it didn't help at all
I am NOT proud of this but I hadn't do
it again
after the third time I'm not proud of
this either but I gave the cat to my
in-laws Oh judge me guys are so much fun
I love you guys like I said I'm very
happy to have a wife I I didn't think it
was gonna happen my sister thought she
needed to step in when I was you know
living at home there she said I'm
setting you up on a blind date
I said why she said I'm tired of looking
at your face you need my help
away what can you tell me about the girl
all she would say is she had a wonderful
personality is it good enough for me
so the day of the date came and this is
gonna sound like a non sequitur but this
is really kind of important to what I'm
about to tell you my dad moves pianos
for a living
and I was helping him move a piano the
day of the date and changed the dolly
out from under the piano for another one
the dolly broke and it crushed my foot
so when I was walking up to her door I
had the most painful foot and I was just
grimacing as I walked up to her door
that was the first part that went wrong
the second was I had a can of red cream
soda in my hand which would you remember
the 80s we loved red cream soda pop
anything with fizz and dye we were so
excited about that
and it was a half-empty Canada that I
want to help be holding this when I meet
this girl I'd be tacky so I get up to
the door I'll slam down the soda as fast
as I can't throw the can in the bushes
because that's how we recycle aluminum
back in the 80s yeah they try to get any
air out that might have developed knock
on the door meet the girl with the nice
personality and get on with our lives
that was my plan and I caught up to the
door and it didn't seem like anyone was
home okay and I started slamming down
the soda a little too fast you know it's
burn and tears are going down my eyes
but I'm getting it done and I hear a
click and I turn and there the door
opens and there she is the girl with the
nice personality and she's stunningly
gorgeous which I wasn't prepared for
have you ever had a panic attack in
front of someone and tried to pretend
you weren't it's just you vibrating just
kind of look at
she said hello I shifted my weight to my
bad foot and what came out was
[Applause]
how's it going that's when her dad came
up to investigate what was taking his
daughter out city all right there son
yeah I'm fine in like an idiot I started
drinking the soda a kid he said
we're in a fight why you limpin like
that I said and I quote oh I got hurt
when I was changing my dolly when I
heard the words that had just come out
of my mouth I shot red cream soda out of
my nose I was wearing white jeans at the
time like merry Christmas everyone I
don't know why she went on the date I
think it was just morbid curiosity she
wanted to talk to me I had soda burning
in my sinuses or have you ever lost hope
I did hear it was who's this beautiful
creature and we had nothing in common
she was smart she was sophisticated she
didn't have food on her clothes you
gotta have something in common
we had nothing and I lost hope but at
the pizza place I said something kind of
funny and she shot Dr Pepper out of her
now we've been married for 24 years
[Applause]
she is so happy like I mentioned we have
four kids now so we've gone to Lamaze
four times to me that was the hardest
part about the whole experience was
Lamaze class they don't pull any punches
do them and we're gonna see a film I'm
like alright how bad could it be it's
the first day you know cesarean section
a cut above natural childbirth no
cesarean you're cutting through to get
the baby you know I'm not a doctor but
isn't that hard on women I think it's
harder on the baby though cuz when
you're born the right way the way you're
supposed to be born I think that's such
a slow process that I think the kid
thinks it's his idea
I wonder what's down here
the door
when you're born cesarean section it's
not slow at all I mean you're in the
womb you're in the room imagine how
horrible would be if it happened to you
you know you're the baby relaxing in a
nice warm jacuzzi and suddenly the roof
opens up a giant hand grabs your head
Yanks you out of the building you turn
to see a mass giant with a knife
that's a bad day
but that wasn't even the worst part it
was the small group class discussions
we're gonna talk about pregnancy issues
it was a nurse at a whiteboard nine of
us in a semicircle around the nurse snow
is falling in northern Minnesota from
where I'm from snow is falling it's the
middle of June today class we're gonna
talk about the proper color of amniotic
fluid please be quiet it needs to be
clear amniotic fluid needs to be cleared
she starts talking about all the colors
it shouldn't be i'm turning all those
colors but not my wife cuz pregnant
women are amazing she's watching this
gross presentation drinking a five
gallon thing on ice water like it's no
big deal but pregnant women can be
clumsy and she dropped that ice water
right between her knees just and I
didn't see what happened I'm like her
water broke just broke the glass freaked
out clear
which is typical for Minnesota children
you guys have so much for us to thank
you so much
[Applause]